<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cleanup on Wild Rydes Web Application</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/</link><description>Recent content in Cleanup on Wild Rydes Web Application</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:35:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:35:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/overview/</guid><description>This page provides instructions for cleaning up the resources created during the preceding modules.</description></item><item><title>Module 4</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/module4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/module4/</guid><description>3. Module 4 - REST API Cleanup Delete the REST API created in module 4. There is a Delete API option in the Actions drop-down when you select your API in the Amazon API Gateway Console.
✅ Step-by-step directions
Go to the Amazon API Gateway Console Select the API you created in module 4. Expand the Actions drop-down and choose Delete API. Enter the name of your API when prompted and choose Delete API.</description></item><item><title>Module 3</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/module3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/module3/</guid><description>2. Module 3 - Serverless Backend Cleanup Delete the AWS Lambda function, IAM role and Amazon DynamoDB table you created in module 3.
✅ Step-by-step directions
Lambda Function Go to the AWS Lambda console Select the %INITIALS%-RequestUnicorn function you created in module 3. From the Actions drop-down, choose Delete function. Choose Delete when prompted to confirm. IAM Role Go to the AWS IAM Console Select Roles from the navigation menu.</description></item><item><title>Module 2</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/module2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/module2/</guid><description>3. Module 2 - User Management Cleanup Delete the Amazon Cognito User Pool
✅ Step-by-step directions
Go to the Amazon Cognito Console Choose Manage your User Pools. Select the user pool you created in module 2. ⚠️ Ensure you have not selected another workshop participant&amp;rsquo;s user pool! If you forgot the name of your Cognito User Pool, refer to User Management for instructions on how to retrieve it. Choose Delete Pool in the upper right corner of the page.</description></item><item><title>Module 1</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/module1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/module1/</guid><description>4. Module 1 - Web Application Cleanup Delete the AWS Amplify Console application and optionally the AWS CodeCommit or GitHub repository created:
✅ Step-by-step directions
For the Amplify Console web applcation: Launch the Amplify Console console page. Select the application you launched today. From Actions in the top right corner, select Delete App Complete the application deletion process. For the CodeCommit repository: Open the AWS CodeCommit console Select the radio button next to the repository created today.</description></item><item><title>CloudWatch Logs</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/cloudwatchlogs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/cloudwatchlogs/</guid><description>5. CloudWatch Logs Cleanup AWS Lambda automatically creates a new log group per function in Amazon CloudWatch Logs and writes logs to it when your function is invoked. You should delete the log group for the RequestUnicorn function.
✅ Step-by-step directions
From the AWS Console click Services then select CloudWatch under Management Tools. Choose Log Groups underneath Logs in the navigation menu. Select the /aws/lambda/%INITIALS%-RequestUnicorn log group. If you have many log groups in your account, you can type /aws/lambda/%INITIALS%-RequestUnicorn into the Filter text box, to easily locate the log group.</description></item><item><title>Cloud9</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/cloud9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/cleanup/cloud9/</guid><description>6. Cloud9 Cleanup Delete the Cloud9 Development environment created today.
✅ Step-by-step directions
Launch the Cloud9 console page. Select the environment you launched today. From the top navigation, select Delete Complete the application deletion process.</description></item></channel></rss>