<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Static Web Hosting on Wild Rydes Web Application</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/</link><description>Recent content in Static Web Hosting on Wild Rydes Web Application</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:41:51 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/overview/</guid><description>In this module you&amp;rsquo;ll configure AWS Amplify Console to host the static resources for your web application. In subsequent modules you&amp;rsquo;ll add dynamic functionality to these pages using JavaScript to call remote RESTful APIs built with AWS Lambda and Amazon API Gateway.
Architecture Overview The architecture for this module is very straightforward. All of your static web content including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, images and other files will be managed by AWS Amplify Console and served via Amazon CloudFront.</description></item><item><title>Region</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/region/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/region/</guid><description>1. Region Selection Use a single region - US East (N. Virginia), also known as us-east-1, for the duration of this workshop. Please select US East (N. Virginia) in the top right corner.
Once you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen a region, you should deploy all of the resources for this workshop there. Make sure you select your region from the dropdown in the upper right corner of the AWS Console before getting started.</description></item><item><title>Repository</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/repository/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 15:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/repository/</guid><description>2. Create the git repository We will use AWS CodeCommit to host your site&amp;rsquo;s repository. CodeCommit is included in the AWS Free Tier.
CodeCommit helper The AWS Cloud9 development environment comes with AWS managed temporary credentials that are associated with your IAM user. You use these credentials with the AWS git-remote-codecommit tool (A Git Remote Helper that makes it easier to interact with AWS CodeCommit). This tool is installed in Cloud9 by default.</description></item><item><title>Deploy</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/deploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/deploy/</guid><description>3. Deploy the site with the AWS Amplify Console Next you&amp;rsquo;ll use the AWS Amplify Console to deploy the website you&amp;rsquo;ve just commited to git. The Amplify Console takes care of the work of setting up a place to store your static web application code and provides a number of helpful capabilities to simplify both the lifecycle of that application as well as enable best practices.
✅ Step-by-step directions
Launch the Amplify Console Underneath Get Started, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a section titled **Host your web app&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>Modify</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/modify/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/modify/</guid><description>4. Modify the website The AWS Amplify Console will rebuild and redeploy the app when it detects changes to the connected repository. Make a change to the main page to test out this process.
✅ Step-by-step directions
From your Cloud9 environment open the index.html file in the /wild-rydes/public/ directory of the repository.
Modify the title line:
&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;wildrydes&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; So that it says:
&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Wild Rydes - Rydes of the Future!</description></item><item><title>Recap</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/recap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/staticwebhosting/recap/</guid><description>⭐ Recap 🔑 AWS Amplify Console makes it easy to deploy static websites with continuous integration and continuous delivery. It is capable of building more complicated JavaScript framework-based applications and shows you a preview of your application as it renders on popular mobile platforms.
🔧 In this module, you&amp;rsquo;ve created a static website which will be the base for our Wild Rydes business.
Next ✅ Proceed to the next module, User Management, where you&amp;rsquo;ll configure Amazon Cognito User Pool with the AWS Amplify CLI to manage our application&amp;rsquo;s users.</description></item></channel></rss>