<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Management on Wild Rydes Web Application</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/</link><description>Recent content in User Management on Wild Rydes Web Application</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:44:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/overview/</guid><description>In this module you&amp;rsquo;ll use the AWS Amplify CLI to create an Amazon Cognito User Pool to manage your users' accounts. You&amp;rsquo;ll deploy pages that enable customers to register as a new user, verify their email address, and sign into the site.
Architecture Overview When users visit your website they will first register a new user account. For the purposes of this workshop we&amp;rsquo;ll only require them to provide an email address and password to register.</description></item><item><title>Amplify Cli</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/amplifycli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/amplifycli/</guid><description>1. Initialize AWS Amplify CLi Background The AWS Amplify Command Line Interface (CLI) is a unified toolchain to create, integrate, and manage the AWS cloud services for your app. The Amplify CLI toolchain is designed to work with the Amplify JavaScript library as well as the AWS Mobile SDKs for iOS and Android.
AWS Amplify Authentication module provides Authentication APIs and building blocks for developers who want to create user authentication experiences.</description></item><item><title>User Pool</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/userpool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/userpool/</guid><description>2. Create an Amazon Cognito User Pool using AWS Amplify CLI Background The AWS Amplify Authentication module provides Authentication APIs and building blocks for developers who want to create user authentication experiences.
Amazon Cognito User Pools is a full-featured user directory service to handle user registration, authentication, and account recovery. Amazon Cognito Federated Identities on the other hand, is a way to authorize your users to use AWS services.
Amplify interfaces with User Pools to store your user information.</description></item><item><title>App Client</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/appclient/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/appclient/</guid><description>3.1 Learn Your User Pool&amp;rsquo;s Name A new Cognito User Pool was created for you in previous step. You need to learn the name of newly created user pool, to distinguish it from user pools of other workshop participants. To learn the name, do the following:
✅ Step-by-step directions
In Cloud9 repository, locate wild-rydes/amplify/backend/auth folder.
Locate subfolder prefixed with wildrydes and parameters.json file inside.
In parameters.</description></item><item><title>Create a User</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/createuser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/createuser/</guid><description>4. Create a new user for your user pool Note: Instead of having you write the browser-side code for managing the registration, verification, and sign in flows, we provide a working implementation in the assets you deployed in the first module by using the AWS Amplify Authentication UI component.
The Authenticator component provides basic login/logout functionality for an application, as well as confirmation steps for new user registration and user login.</description></item><item><title>Recap</title><link>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/recap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:42:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marcinbelczewski.github.io/aws-serverless-webapp-workshop/usermanagement/recap/</guid><description>⭐ Recap 🔑 Amazon Cognito provides two different capabilities for managing users, federated identities and user pools. Amazon Cognito user pools handle almost any aspect about managing users, including login credentials, password resets, multifactor authentication and much more!
🔧 In this module you used user pools to create a fully-managed user management system that allows you to authenticate your users and manage their user information. You updated your website to use the user pool, and used the AWS SDKs to provide a signin form on the site.</description></item></channel></rss>